Rob Williford

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Freelance

iii 10/2022 - 05/2023

Remote - Denver, CO

Various

- · Freelance software development for a local enterprise company in Denver
- · Contributed to the billing team focused on improving user experience
- · Specialized in C# Xamarin and TypeScript Angular development
- Guided newer developers and conducted an informative session about C# and TypeScript, aiding a tech shift for the mobile user experience
- Facilitated a shift from C# Xamarin to Angular PWA with Ionic for mobile services
- · Work sourced through Unison Systems

Senior Software Engineer

Blackbaud

= 11/2021 - 10/2022

Remote - Denver, CO

Computer Software Company

- · (Full-time) Full-time role utilizing .NET/Azure for comprehensive, cloudbased fullstack software engineering
- Contributed to the web-based edition of the Financial Edge software's accounting segment using Angular/RxJS for front-end and C#/Azure for back-end
- Managed all aspects of software implementations, improving features and fixing defects from UI to Database systems
- Participated as a member of an internal team refining interview techniques for evaluating prospective software engineers
- · Collaborated engineering org wide both with primary team and cross-team efforts to deliver and refine solutions for both product and operations

Senior Software Engineer

Freelance

= 09/2020 - 10/2021

Remote - Raleigh, NC

Various

- Freelance full-stack software development consulting using React, Java/Spring, NodeJS, and Python3/Flask on various client projects
- Developed full-stack React and Java/Spring software for an enterprise freight platform
- Contributed to a full-stack JavaScript platform for entertainment events during COVID lockdowns
- Used Python3 and Flask for a healthcare application managing COVID vaccine inventory and appointment scheduling
- Built a backend service on AWS using JS, Lambda, Terraform, and ECS for a regional energy company to automate electricity permits for new residential and commercial construciton projects
- Provided proven expertise in analyzing client needs and delivering customized software solutions in a diverse array of operational/domain contexts

Software Engineer

PrecisionHawk

== 11/2019 - 09/2020

Hybrid - Raleigh, NC

Drone/Software Solutions for Energy and Agriculture

- · (Full-time) Served as the sole full-stack engineer, using React and |ava8/Open|DK on an AWS infrastructure
- Developed an application for energy companies to monitor their infrastructure via drone imaging data - Enhanced user interfaces and optimized data
- Enhanced user interfaces and optimized data services for grid node street view using React/JS and Java
- Increased data pipeline processing via parallelization for lidar and infrared imaging data
- Designed and implemented an authorization migration strategy from Auth0 to AWS Cognito using Python3
- · Adapted quickly to emerging technologies and tools to meet project needs

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack generalist with over 7 years of industry experience interested in fullstack or platform engineering opportunities. I like pushing the boundaries of what people think is possible. I enjoy working on applications that have the potential to shift paradigms, and drive large impact. I value and like to help cultivate empathy and collaboration in a team oriented environment, and am an advocate for work-life balance in company cultures.

SKILLS

Languages



Frameworks



Infrastructure



Cloud



EXPERIENCE PASSIONS

Software Engineer

= 03/2019 - 10/2019

Environment

Cloud, IT, and IoT solutions

(Full-time) Developed automated solutions for financial data hosted on

- Built a microservice for financial services data instance migration using Python3
- Assisted in architecting, designing, and creating a cloud-native PaaS with a distributed Go back-end, ReactJS front-ends, hosted on IBMCloud
- Worked on building a new cloud-native PaaS with a distributed systems back-end implemented in Go, ReactJS front-ends, and using Kubernetes hosted on IBMCloud.
- Improved data-streaming capabilities for financial metadata and file aggregation using Go and imlemented Terraform infrastructure as code for configuration of Kubernetes clusters and associated container image repository on IBMCloud
- Developed effective strategies for optimizing cloud resources and reducing operational costs
- Fasciliated cross-team technical collaborative efforts among teams globally distributed
- Member of team of five that received a CIO technical achievement award

Software Engineer

Cisco

Digital Security and Networking Solutions

- (Contract) Full-stack web development for a software image security platform
- Built and maintained API integrations with internal and external government agencies
- Enhanced user interface and page navigation mechanisms utilizing JS and
- Expanded the functionality of back-end services and fixed bugs using Ruby and contributed to security libraries written Java, Python, and Go
- Developed proficiency in maintaining and enhancing security automation for security compliance standards
- Worked in a cross-displinary team that also involved interfacing with offshore teams

EDUCATION

B.S. Environmental Science/Mathematics

- Physics/Mathematics
- **Open Source**
- **Traveling**